<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>WhoIsToyo?</title>
    <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo" />
    <updated>2024-06-27T07:52:40+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Toyo</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo</id>

    <entry>
        <title>In Die Fabrik Für Ein Besseres Morgen Falls Es Das Gibt</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/in-die-fabrik-fuer-ein-besseres-morgen-falls-es-das-gibt.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/in-die-fabrik-fuer-ein-besseres-morgen-falls-es-das-gibt.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/17/0d99b42b124bd8c6730e9ac77d412d712255eb2f.png" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:52:40+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/17/0d99b42b124bd8c6730e9ac77d412d712255eb2f.png" alt="" />
                    This is a game meant to showcase and make use of the Playstation Vita integration for LittleBigPlanet 2, the theme is based around&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/17/0d99b42b124bd8c6730e9ac77d412d712255eb2f.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This is a game meant to showcase and make use of the Playstation Vita integration for LittleBigPlanet 2, the theme is based around a location from the official story mode. Using a PS Vita alongside the PS3 you have to solve all kinds of puzzles and there's also some funny dialogue and interactions with Clive (also a character from the official story mode)</p>
<p>For a lot of puzzles i had to recreate the enviroments i already made for the base PS3 for the PS Vita so you could interact with things on your Vita and see the result of your actions on the big screen, while also taking into account that you have a lot less assets available on Vita while linked to the PS3 like this, syncing the positions of certain movable materials across both screens was also very tricky, and there are still some bugs, but its working.</p>
<p>I also made sure to pay close attention to the design and i feel like i definitely succeded to an extent, all in all i would say its a pretty solid short puzzle platformer, it's a shame that so few people own both a PS3 and a PS Vita (not to mention they need to own LittleBigPlanet 2) so very few people ever played it.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Creator Pack 3</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/creator-pack-3.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/creator-pack-3.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/16/c0b2fd1803279fdb5c0694fa03a9d3cf131b79a0.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:43:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/16/c0b2fd1803279fdb5c0694fa03a9d3cf131b79a0.png" alt="" />
                    This isn't a regular game, its a collection of helpful mechanisms and mechanic logic pieces as well as pictures of Super Mario Bros&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/16/c0b2fd1803279fdb5c0694fa03a9d3cf131b79a0.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This isn't a regular game, its a collection of helpful mechanisms and mechanic logic pieces as well as pictures of Super Mario Bros and Spongebob, it's made in and primarily for LittleBigPlanet 1 since in the entires following after you can properly code using visual programming, so i replicated specific logic pieces from the newer entires as mechanisms and gave them out for people to use. Hopefully it helped some people.</p>
<p>Even though this isn't supposed to be a regular game, i still made sure that it had a nice design thats consistent across the whole level and that everything was presented well. Also the reason why its called Creator Pack 3 is because there was already an official one by the creators of LittleBigPlanet and a popular fan made one.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Terror auf der Frount Crisby 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby-2.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby-2.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/15/5d2ba848f88414f089026f229afa0bcb06355a63.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:31:01+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/15/5d2ba848f88414f089026f229afa0bcb06355a63.png" alt="" />
                    This is the sequel to Terror auf der Frount Crisby and i'd say its definitely higher quality than the first one, this of course&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/15/5d2ba848f88414f089026f229afa0bcb06355a63.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This is the sequel to <a href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby.html"></a><a href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby.html">Terror auf der Frount Crisby</a> and i'd say its definitely higher quality than the first one, this of course is also made in collaboration with InfinityZockerA9. In the sequel there are more cutscenes and special gadets and interactions as you try to escape the ship you've crashed on, including a special boss and the conclusion of the adventure.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Terror auf der Frount Crisby</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/terror-auf-der-frount-crisby.html</id>
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:24:19+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is a level made in collaboration with InfinityZockerA9, its a platformer set in space with a bit of narrative mixed in. There&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is a level made in collaboration with InfinityZockerA9, its a platformer set in space with a bit of narrative mixed in. There are bunch of obstacles to overcome on your spaceship, especially when things start going south.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Frostige Panik</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/frostige-panik.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/frostige-panik.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/13/f0c6fa3ab524a00fcb6bf37e56763fa5c1142f87.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:21:05+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/13/f0c6fa3ab524a00fcb6bf37e56763fa5c1142f87.png" alt="" />
                    This is a survival game i made in LittleBigPlanet Vita, you have to avoid a bunch of obstacles and if you die, the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/13/f0c6fa3ab524a00fcb6bf37e56763fa5c1142f87.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This is a survival game i made in LittleBigPlanet Vita, you have to avoid a bunch of obstacles and if you die, the game ends. It's obviously DC Comics based i made sure to add quite a bit of design to the enviroment.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Dreams</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/dreams.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/dreams.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/12/b04416262cbaf5751b159dd2c3dbaed99399568b.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:17:48+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/12/b04416262cbaf5751b159dd2c3dbaed99399568b.png" alt="" />
                    Dreams is a short narrative game i made in LittleBigPlanet Vita, it's quite mysterious and ominious, with makes sense considering its about dreams.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/12/b04416262cbaf5751b159dd2c3dbaed99399568b.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>Dreams is a short narrative game i made in LittleBigPlanet Vita, it's quite mysterious and ominious, with makes sense considering its about dreams. You basically transition between all kinds of dream landscapes until the end, this one's more story based so i don't really want to spoil a lot.</p>
<p>Its very impressive how a Playstation Vita is powerful enough to basically run a whole game engine.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Der boden ist lava</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/der-boden-ist-lava.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/der-boden-ist-lava.html</id>
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-27T07:12:51+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This is a level that i made together with an old friend InfinityZockerA9, i made most of the programming etc though. In the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>This is a level that i made together with an old friend InfinityZockerA9,  i made most of the programming etc though. In the game you there are 2 maps you can choose, one being space based, one being canyon based and every few seconds the ground turns into lava (or starts burning to be more exact) and you have to jump onto the objects in your enviroment to survive, as time goes on more and more objects dissapear so it gets harder and harder to survive.</p>
<p>There are also rewards for hitting certain score milestones, the score increases every time you survive a wave. It's a pretty neat little game that has quite a bit of replayability. In retrospect we could have definitely expanded on it by adding more maps, adding a shop with upgrades to add more depth to the gameplay etc but it's fine the way it is.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Real life RPG 2</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-2.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-2.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/10/ed01755ae3cbc66a3ccc8a71b88fd9d72769b795.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-24T16:09:08+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/10/ed01755ae3cbc66a3ccc8a71b88fd9d72769b795.png" alt="" />
                    After the live event that happened back in Real life RPG 1 this sequel came out, featuring a brand new map and a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/10/ed01755ae3cbc66a3ccc8a71b88fd9d72769b795.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>After the live event that happened back in <a href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-1.html">Real life RPG 1</a> this sequel came out, featuring a brand new map and a bunch of new features, an old friend named InfinityZockerA9 helped me a bit with it, but i did all of the programming and most other things, this is one of the biggest game's i've ever made, it has so much content we had serious stability issues, and even now the game always crashes when you're playing with more than 2 people, for a while we coudn't even get into the game ourselves because it was too overloaded with stuff.</p>
<p>This game features a better looking map than the first one, house upgrades, dreams, a mine, upgrades to buy, secret minigames and a lot more, it even saves your progress now and the game doesn't end anymore after a certain time limit, meaning if you buy a house for example, it will still be there the next time to play the game.</p>
<p>We even used to have npc's that move around the map but we had to scrap it as it would make the performance even worse. There were never any life events for this part though, the game is pretty much a finished, unevolving work.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Real life RPG 1</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-1.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-1.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/9/a403aa1e70bb8c0321ad405e15643620962a712b.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-24T15:59:27+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/9/a403aa1e70bb8c0321ad405e15643620962a712b.png" alt="" />
                    I wanted to do something special, this was a little game where you could buy houses, hang out and do all kinds of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/9/a403aa1e70bb8c0321ad405e15643620962a712b.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>I wanted to do something special, this was a little game where you could buy houses, hang out and do all kinds of other activities, but eventually, the world would end, and you would be teleported to a shop where you could buy in-game cosmetic items and more with stuff you earned while playing the game. </p>
<p>I added more content to the game as time went on, but i decided to do it in a unique way, for the most important updates i decided to do live events, similar to those you would see in games like Fortnite, these would be one-time events that would build up lore and story and also update the map with more content. I recorded the last live event on YouTube.</p>
<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BFYlNUGuG_g?si=_QLfbHmXrntPzimb" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></div>
<p>A problem with these live events would be that they weren't officially supported by the engine and game platform i used (LittleBigPlanet) so i had to do some workarounds to get it to work (i even faked interaction between other players on the server), there wasn't actually a server being updated live, in reality i updated the whole game a bit before the announced live event would start, knowing that the players of the old version will have been kicked out of the game by now, since the game ends eventually, as i mentioned. So that new build would contain the live event and after the live event is over the players would either be transfered to an unlisted version of the newest build with all of the changes made by the live event being in effect, the new map etc, or the changes would just be done on the live event build they're currently on too, then i updated the build while they were still in the game to the post-live event version, so if they'd leave the game and rejoin they woudn't see the live event again and instead the aftermath of the event that happened.</p>
<p>The problem with this is: what would happen if a player joined right before the live event was to start but after i already updated to the live event build, they would be slightly out of sync, but thats not even that bad, the real issue lies within what would happen if someone decided to restart the level or leave it during the event and rejoin, the live event would repeat!</p>
<p>Anyway, i dont think that ever really happened though, so thats good. Eventually the final live event lead up to the entire map being destroyed and <a href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/real-life-rpg-2.html">Real life RPG 2</a> to come out!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The secret garden</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/the-secret-garden.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/the-secret-garden.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/8/2c3279234768ae883613d7e2e79f80fea325a985.png" medium="image" />
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-24T15:18:24+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/8/2c3279234768ae883613d7e2e79f80fea325a985.png" alt="" />
                    This was the first proper level i ever created in LittleBigPlanet and the start of my YouTube channel. I made a YouTube video&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/8/2c3279234768ae883613d7e2e79f80fea325a985.png" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>This was the first proper level i ever created in LittleBigPlanet and the start of my YouTube channel. I made a YouTube video on it, i hoped that the level was so good that it would get me the the prize crown (a reward given out to the best creations on LBP) but it didnt, i can see why. But the level was fine, especially for its time.</p>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NiFnMLjf68o?si=1H5NBb9RED7m07s3" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></figure>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
