<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>WhoIsToyo?</title>
    <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo" />
    <updated>2024-06-23T21:01:25+02:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Toyo</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/introduction.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/introduction.html</id>

        <updated>2024-06-23T20:33:19+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Hey! I'm Toyo and i'm interested in all kinds of tech, game developement and art. Over the years i've gained a lot of&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Hey! I'm Toyo and i'm interested in all kinds of tech, game developement and art.<br>Over the years i've gained a lot of knowledge about the general concepts of programming,<br>largely through a game series called "LittleBigPlanet".<br><br>LittleBigPlanet introduced me to the concept of programming and game developement<br>at an early age, over the years i mastered it until i was pretty much able to programm anything<br>in it. It's shocking how powerful the visual programming language of that series is,<br>i wished it would've been on pc and allowed you to export your games but sadly everything<br>that you create in it is locked to inside of the game.<br><br>In the meantime they've also released another engine-game called "Dreams" but at this<br>point i wasn't dedicated to fully learning that anymore, it also has the exact same problems<br>as its predecessor.<br><br>So now i'm starting to learn "real" game developement engines and im going to document my progress<br>and everything between inside of my blogs in the hopes that it may help somebody else and also for myself.<br>In addition to that i am also going to showcase my already existing game projects on here and provide<br>some insights into their creation processes.<br><br>At this point i am also running a custom server for the aforementioned game series as the official servers<br>have (unsurprisingly) been shut down. I'm using open source software for this, which is convenient for me<br>as i'm actually not very experienced in networking. We also have a relatively big team at this point alongside<br>a Discord Server, it's my most successful project by far so there will be a seperate page dedicated to it.<br><br>I also have an (inactive) YouTube channel and a lot more social media, almost all of which you'll be able to<br>find on my social media page. I'm also learning html and css right now so this website will definitely<br>improve in functionality and design as time goes on and i gain more experience.<br>Oh, and im also bilingual, i speak both german and english fluently and see both as my "native"<br>languages, since i've grown up learning both. I use English primarily though, for pretty much everything<br>that doesn't involve speaking with people in real life (including thinking most of the time) as i live in Germany.<br><br>Anyway, i hope that's enough of an introduction and that you'll enjoy following my journey!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>One of my Projects</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/one-of-my-projects.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/one-of-my-projects.html</id>
            <category term="Projects"/>

        <updated>2024-06-16T20:51:27+02:00</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Infinite</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/infinite.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/infinite.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/3/Application-Banner.jpg" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-06-16T20:49:55+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/3/Application-Banner.jpg" alt="" />
                    The official servers for the game series LittleBigPlanet shut down a while ago, and Infinite is one of the custom servers aiming to&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/media/posts/3/Application-Banner.jpg" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>The official servers for the game series LittleBigPlanet shut down a while ago, and Infinite is one of the custom servers aiming to bring back its online functionality. To access the servers users have to modify their Playstation 3 by jailbreaking it so that the eboot.bin file (which is essentially the executable file of the game) can be modefied to connect to our server, instead of the old one, which is, of course, shut down.</p>
<p>I'm lucky to have a passionate and dedicated Team by my side!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Choosing an Engine</title>
        <author>
            <name>Toyo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/choosing-an-engine.html"/>
        <id>https://oo1toyo1oo.github.io/WhoIsToyo/choosing-an-engine.html</id>

        <updated>2024-06-16T20:46:37+02:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Welcome to my first blog post! So i have decided that im going to be primarily using Gamemaker Studio 2 for 2D games,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Welcome to my first blog post!<br><br>So i have decided that im going to be primarily using Gamemaker Studio 2<br>for 2D games, and Unreal Engine for 3D games. I have tested Gamemaker<br>for a while now and i find it to be easy and convenient to use,<br>it also only requires a one-time fee to start commercially selling your games.<br>Most engines are going to take a cut once your game has sold a certrain number<br>of copies, but not Gamemaker (or Godot). But the downside to Gamemaker is that<br>you can't create 3D games, at least not without tricking the hell out of<br>the engine. So im going to be using Unreal for 3D, i've been considering Unity,<br>however since the whole drama that happened where they wanted to charge game<br>devs for installations, i don't think that's a good idea.<br><br>Both Unreal and Unity feature a visual programming language, similar to the one in used back in LittleBigPlanet. So i'd probably be able to get into it pretty quickly, however<br>for Gamemaker at least i do want to use its dedicated gml code as much as possible,<br>because it would improve my traditonal coding skills, for Unreal i think i'll use<br>their blueprint system primarily though, as they only offer c++ as an alternative<br>which im not very interested in learning right now, blueprints seem to be powerful enough.<br><br>I had also been learning Renpy a while back, it's an engine and programming language for the developement of visual novels and it's very easy to use, i feel like i got the most<br>importing things figured out about it, right now i dont really want to focus on visual<br>novel stuff though, but it's nice to know i suppose.<br><br>Alright so i'm currently watching a bunch of tutorials on Gamemaker, i already learned some stuff but its all still very basic. And without tutorials i cant really make much at all,<br>so im kind of trapped in tutorial hell right now. I'll try to participate in Game Jams<br>as soon as possible as its the quickest and best way to learn in game developement from what i've seen.<br><br>But first i want to finish a short experimental Platformer game first called Rainhiker,<br>so i can gain some more skill before actually participating in any Game Jams.<br>I only have a rough concept for the game right now i do think i can make something<br>out of it...</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
